Preliminary Inventory of the Pavel Aleksandrovich Bazarov Papers, 1904-1906
Hoover Institution Archives
Pavel Aleksandrovich Bazarov Papers,
1904-1906
XX065
Bazarov, Pavel Aleksandrovich
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, orders, field maps, correspondence, and clippings, relating to the Russo-Japanese War.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Kuropatkin, A. N.; Russia. Armiia--Officers; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905; Russia
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE ON THE RUSSO-JAPANESE WAR, 1904-1905
  - Clippings from newspapers (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Foreign military agents attached to the Russian Army
    - Awards, Recommendations for (Folder 2)
    - Information received from (Folder 3)
    - Instructions for (Folder 4)
    - Reports regarding their assignments (Folder 5)
    - Those remaining in Mukden after the retreat (Folder 6)
    - Those stationed in Vladivostok (Folder 7)
  - Japanese Army, Information on (gathered by the Russian military forces) (Folder 8)
  - Kuropatkin, Aleksei N.
    - "Telegrama Ego Imperatorskomu Velichestvu ot General-Ad'iutanta Kuropatkina Ot 29 Avgusta 1904 goda No. 8719" (Telegram to His Imperial Highness From Adjutant General Kuropatkin On August 29, 1904, No. 8719) (Folder 9)
    - Time schedule, 1904 January - 1905 February (Folder 10)
  - Manchurian Army, instructions and orders (Folder 11)
  - Maps and diagrams of combat areas and surrounding regions (Folder 12)
  - Mylov, S., "Iz Opyta Tekushchei Voiny" (From the Experience of the Ongoing War), n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Russian naval operations (Folder 14)
  - Stessel', Adjutant General, "Glavneishie Prakticheskie Vyvody Iz Boevogo Opyta Na Kvantunskom Poluostove Otnositel'no Deistvii Voisk Protiv Iapontsev" (The Most Important Conclusions From the Combat Experience On the Kvantunsk Peninsula Regarding the Military Operations Against the Japanese), 1904 August 20 (Folder 15)
  - Strategic plans against the Japanese (Folder 16)
  - Tsikhovich, Lieutenant-Colonel, "Kratkoe Opisanie Predstoiashchikh Deistvii" (Brief Description of Forthcoming Operations), December 22, 1904 (Folder 17)